

INNOVATION & AUTOMATION · AWS ENTHUSIAST · DEVOPS & OPERATIONS · PHOTOGRAPHER

□ (+91) 9886845649 | Schetan.hireholi@gmail.com | Achetanhireholi.me | □ chetan-hireholi | □ chetanhireholi

Summary _____

Hacking my way through in DevOps+Operations Team since 2016.

Specialties: AWS, Prometheus, Grafana, Cloud Foundry, Apache Superset, Automated CI/CD using Jenkins, Gitlab, Docker, PostgreSQL

I'm involved in a multi facet role: Developer, Solution Designing & Mentoring.

In the team, I'm in-charge of bringing in innovative solutions to help my team work efficiently and achieve the desired Key Performance Indicators.

Experience ____

Philips Healthcare, Software Technologist I

April 2020 - Current

KEY SKILLS: CLOUD FOUNDRY | JENKINS | DOCKER | PROMETHEUS | GRAFANA | APACHE SUPERSET | TASK

AUTOMATION | ACCOUNTABILITY | RISK ASSESSMENT | PROJECT MANAGEMENT | MENTORING |

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- Became a single point of contact in my team to gather requirements and help strategize CI/CD frameworks.
- Implemented CI/CD frameworks using **Jenkins**. Extending this framework to 'one-click' direct deployments to Cloud Foundry.
- Demonstrate creativity and innovation in implementing critical dashboards for Production environments using Apache Superset.

Philips Healthcare, Software Engineer I - Software DevOps Engineer II

June 2016 - March 2020

Key skills: Cloud Foundry | AWS (EC2, IAM) | Prometheus | Grafana | Nginx | PostGreSQL | Python | Go | Java | Requirements Gathering | Stakeholder communications | Security conscious code | Q&A Tool validation

- Implemented a **real time production monitoring mechanism using Prometheus and Grafana** by replacing New Relic. This proved to be cost efficient and **saved around \$110k of licensing cost**. Altered Prometheus exporters for customised metrics for monitoring of PostGre, Cloud Foundry, EC2 instances in AWS. Configured a reverse proxy using Nginx and implemented basic authentication for security. Additionally, configured alerting mechanisms via PagerDuty, Slack/Teams bots and Emails.
- Played a key role in driving and managing a board meeting including various Scientists, Remote Monitoring Engineers and Stake-holders where critical production issues are discussed and deployed proactive and predictive models on Rapid Minder/On-Premises/Cloud environments.
- Played a **key role in on-boarding ServiceNow** to the Production environment. Was involved in various activities such as: gathering requirements, setting up end2end work-flows, validating, passing on knowledge to the teams and communicating to stakeholders.
- Development efforts: Helped in **implementing a Key Performance Indicator dashboard on Java/Spring-boot/AngularJS** enabling the Management to get real-time Production metric updates

Philips Healthcare, Project Trainee (Internship)

July 2015 - June 2016

KEY SKILLS: JAVA | GEMINI(TICKETING TOOL) | SERVICE NOW | MICROSOFT TEAM FOUNDATION SERVER (TFS)

- Was involved in **troubleshooting P1 P4** client bugs and incident reports.
- Increased team productivity by 20% through automating essential graphs and reporting which enabled the Management to get centralized view on tickets and resource consumption via Kanban and Scrum boards on Gemini and Microsoft TFS.

Skills & Tools

Programming: Python, Shell, Java **Web technologies:** HTML5/CSS, NodeJS, Nginx

Operating Systems: Linux (CentOS, Ubuntu), Windows, Mac

Databases: PostGreSQL, Vertica, MySQL

Cloud Platforms: Cloud foundry, Github/Gitlab, AWS (S3, EC2, IAM, Route53, RDS)

DevOps Tools: Jenkins, Docker, Prometheus, Grafana, Superset, Git

Certification & Awards

ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management

LICENSE GR750279439CH

Dec. 2016 - Present

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Program Increment and Spot Awards for living the behaviour

PHILIPS HEALTHCARE 2017, 2018

Education

PES University

M.Tech. In Software Engineering

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

June 2014 - August 2016

July 2010 - July 2014

Visvesvaraya Technological University

B.Tech. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Extracurricular Activities

HackathonsBengaluru, Karnataka, India

PHILIPS HEALTHCARE, HACTOBERFEST

2016, 2017, 2019

- Automated prescription with the help of Amazon Alexa [In collabration with Philips Research]
- Automated deployments to specific environments
- · Contributed to Open Source projects in GitHub

Technical seminarsBengaluru, Karnataka, India

PES University 2015, 2016

- Future of Internet of Things. Documentation available for download on SlideShare: click- PowerPoint presentation
- Crime Analysis and Prediction using Data Mining. Documentation available for download on SlideShare: click- PowerPoint presentation

Photography

 ${\sf Genre: Street, Portraits, Black and White.}$

2018

- Featured on Unsplash Editorial. (993,496 views and over 3,672 downloads)
- Associated photo-projects with CARE (Charlie's Animal Rescue Center) for animal adoptions.